Guide to the Lin Carter Papers, 1900s-2001 and undated RL.11079
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1900s-1990 and undated; 1
  - Unidentified Writings (likely by Carter), 2
    - The Sawhorse and the Gingham Dog/Princess Dorothy and the Calico Cat, undated (Box 5)
      typescripts with handwritten notes; sequels; "Princess Dorothy and the Calico Cat" ending with the note "To be Continued in Glinda Meets the Little Witch"
    - Fragment typescript pages with titles (very likely by Carter), undated (Box 5)
      two typescript versions of synopses ("In Tartary: … In Sylvania: …"), typescript titled "4. Trouble in Tartary" (pp. 35-37), typescript pages titled "Bleys" in several versions, typescript titled "1. The Road to Mudville" (pp. 1-4), typescript titled "1. An Appetite for Goozleberries" (p. 1) and "Chapter 1. All Out of Goozleberries!" (p. 6-7), typescript titled "1. The Crown Prince Has No Appetite" (Prince Pancho, no page numbers), typescript titled "Little Birds are dreaming..." (p. 3) and page with the beginning of "Forgetfulness" by Lewis Carroll incl. introductory note by Carter (no page number), typescript page titled "Sabbat Eve," typescript pages titled "The Tree on the Hill," "Ashes," and "The Trap" (no page numbers), typescript page with poemts titled "Lines Upon a Tranquil Brow," "The Keen and the Quing," and "Parsnoops," typescript titled "Prometheus Bound" and "Lemuria Found" (pp. 4-6), typescript titled "How it All Started" on Prince Pancho (no page numbers), typescript including chapters on "How Silly Simon earned..." (pp. 5-20, ch. 1-7), two typescript versions titled "1. Marko Makes Up His Mind," single typescript page titled "The Woods-Wizard" with attached handwritten note, typescript titled "(Part) I. Of Quests and Princes" (pp. 5-23, 30, incl. chapter "1. Three Sought Adventure (sic)," "2. The Country That Wasn't There," and first page of chapter "3. Decisions in Klutzemburg"), typescript titled "1. Villainy in the Void" (pp. 1, 8-11, 13, 15)
    - Fragments typescript pages without titles (very likely by Carter), undated (Box 5)
      typescript (seemingly complete, but without title page) on Atlantis, Slyth the Subtle, Zisque, Sargamus Zelb, et al. (pp. 1-14, ch. 1-4), typescript with name index from "Prince Dru" to "Zarthon the Terrible" (pp. 197-203, end), typescript on Hargrave Dean et. al. (pp. 106-119, end), typescript on time travel (pp. 181-89, end), typescript on King Sancho of Sancho-Panzania (pp. 5-8), typescript on Woody, Koko, et al. (pp. 17-18), typescript on Tip Topsy, Koko, et al. (pp. 17-18), typescript on sorcerer Haon-Door (pp. 1-6), typescript on Harvey Hodges, Krotzenheimer, et al. (pp. 3-26, ch. 1-3), typescript on Azathoth, Gnoph-Keh, Gol-Goroth, Ghizguth, Hastur, et al. (no page numbers), typescript on Marquis de Carabas, Princess Melisandra, et al. (pp. 1-9), typescript on Zun, Lord Zelshathla, Lord Thloom Pitrana, et al. (no page numbers), typescript on Klutzemburg, Clorinda, et al. (pp. 12-17, 20-21, and unpaginated), typescript on Yuggs, Worms of the Eearth, et al. and "Notes" (pp. 203-205), typescript on Thongor, Breygoth, Prince Thar and Zuria of Kathool, et al. (pp. 1, 5-6), typescript on Phariom, Varascus, et al. (pp. 1-4, one page with handwritten notes)
    - Fragment single typescript pages without titles (very likely by Carter), undated (Box 5)
      typescripts
    - Story lists, incomplete, 1979-1982 (Box 9)
      Includes lists of Carter's own works as well as other publications he wanted to acquire, described as "desired titles."
    - Assorted notes, incomplete drafts, undated (Box 9)
  - Writings by Others, 3
    - Adler, Mortimer J.: The Disappearance of Culture (from: Newsweek, August 21, 1978), 1978 Aug. 21 (Box 6)
      xerox copy of article
    - Anderson: The Belfrey, undated (Box 6)
      xerox copy of page 1 of typescript
    - Ashley, Mike: Lin Carter - A Bibliography, 1990 (Box 6)
      typescript of bibliography, incl. letter by Ashley to Bob dated 11/11/1990
    - Ashmead, John, Darrell Schweitzer, and George Scithers: Constructing Scientifiction and Fantasy, 1982 (Box 6)
      print copy
    - Ashton Smith, Clark: Art and Poetry, 1941, 1952, 1961, and undated (Box 6)
      includes sketches (probably by Ashton Smith), typescripts of Smith poems (incl. "Geometries" (08/09/1952), "No title (Awowal, L.C.)," "The Envoys," "The Mirrors of Beauty," "To George Sterling" (11/20/1941), "Song of Author," "Seer of the Cycles," "February" and "Sea-cliff" ((1961)), "Winter Song," "In Time of Absence," "The Looms of Change"); originally included in a folder by Carter labeled "CAS Art"
    - Ashton Smith, Clark: Correspondence by and to Carter and Documents re Ashton Smith, 1970-1973, 1983, and undated (Box 6)
      letters by Roy A. Squires ("RAS") and others to Carter re Ashton Smith (incl. bibliographical lists), "A Listing of The Poems In Manuscript by Clark Ashton Smith in the Berg Collection of the New York City Public Library," newspaper clippings about Ashton Smith (incl. "Such Pulp as Dreams are Made On" by Robert Allerton Parker), lists of publications by Ashton Smith, (incl. booklets by "The Private Press of Roy A. Squires" ("RAS Press") from undated and 1970, two copies of photograph of Ashton Smith with others, xerox copies of official documents of Ashton Smith, various typescript ahd manuscript notes on Ashton Smith publications
    - Ashton Smith, Clark: The Ghoul/The Coming of the White Worm, undated (Box 6)
      xerox copy of story by Ashton Smith from "Other Dimensions" (incomplete), edited xerox copy of typescript with transcript of manuscript of "The Coming of the White Worm (Chapter IX of The Book of Eibon)" by Ashton Smith
    - Ashton Smith, Clark: A Good Embalmer, undated (Box 6)
      xerox copy of story by Smith with letter by Roy A. Squires to Carter dated 03/14/1982
    - Ashton Smith, Clark: Collection of Shorter Texts by and Notes on Ashton Smith, 1940, 1944, 1948, 1971 (Box 6)
      typescript with "Planets and Dimensions," "A Cosmic Novel (Review of "The Wee of Easter Island" by Donald Wandrei)," and "In Appreciation of William Hope Hodgson" by Ashton Smith as well as "Story-ideas without titles"
    - Ashton Smith, Clark: Interview of Henry J. Vester III with Robert Baker Elder, undated (Box 6)
      typescript of interview, handwritten notes and check by Carter
    - Ashton Smith, Clark: Klarkash-Toniana. An Annotated Bibliography by Lin Carter, 1973 July (Box 6)
      typescript with handwritten notes, incl. note "Only original copy. Completed July 1973."
    - Ashton Smith, Clark: Letters by Ashton Smith to George Sterling, 1911-1926 and undated (Box 6)
      typescripts by Carter of letters by Ashton Smith, including a couple of xerox copies of letter manuscripts
    - Ashton Smith, Clark: Letters to Various and Manuscripts by Ashton Smith, 1918, 1931, 1934, 1937 and undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Folder 1: xerox copies, typescript and manuscript copies by Carter; Folder 2: typescripts of stories by Ashton Smith, incl. "The Master of Destruction": "Forward" and "Synopsis," "Shapes of Adamant" and "The Tale of the Prophet Ulon," "The Ocean-World of Alioth (Synopsis)," "Mandor's Enemy," "Slaves of the Black Pillar," "In the Book of Vergama" (incomplete), "Beyond the Rose-Arbor," "Queen of the Sabbat," "Offspring of the Grave," "The Sorceress of Averoigne. The Tower of Istarelle. Synopsis," "Vizaphmal in Ophiuchus," "In a Hashish-Dream (A Tale of Hashish-Land)," "The House of Haon-Dor," "Asharia. A Tale of the Lost Planet," "Nelesis of the Unfinished" (pp. 1-8 and 4-9), "The Dart of Rasasfa," "The Infernal Star," "The Mortuary" and "The Noctuary of Nathan Geast" and "The Token"; both folders were originally contained in one folder labeled by Carter "unpublished Smith letters and manuscripts"
    - Barlow, Robert Hayward: Miscellaneous, 1936, 1976, 1980, and undated (Box 6)
      incl. xerox copies of "The Summons. A Fragment," "A Dim-Remembered Story" with Preface by H. P. Lovecraft (1980), and beginnings of "Annals of the Jinns" stories (incl. "The Flagon of Beauty" (no. 3), "The Sacred Bird" (no. 4), "The Tomb of the God" (no. 5), "The Flower God" (no. 6), "The Little Box" (no. 7), "The Fall of the Three Cities" (no. 8), "The Mirror" (no. 9)); part of letter by Roy A. Squires, typescript of "The Flower God" from the "Annals of Jinns" and untitled story, copy of "The Night Ocean" (with H. P. Lovecraft) from "The Californian" (Vol. IV, Winter, 1936, No. 3 (incomplete, first and last page), another xerox copy of "The Night Ocean" (first page missing), copy of "L'Oceano di Notte" (Italian translation of "The Night Ocean" by Roberta Rambelli, Sept. 1976; incomplete, first and last page); originally folder by Carter labeled "Barlow Stuff"
    - Bell, Joseph: "Howard Phillips Lovecraft: The Books (4) 1915-1986", 1987 (Box 12)
    - Bellairs manuscript: The Two Magicians, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Bierce, Ambrose: An Occurrence at Owl Creek, undated (Box 6)
      xerox copy
    - Boardman, John: Giant of World's End by Lin Carter (sf), undated (Box 6)
    - Brahma, Ernest: Miscellaneous, 1959-1973 (Box 6)
      several copies of articles on Brahma by William White, letters by White to Carter, and some handwritten notes
    - Brennan, Joseph Payne: Wanderson's Waste, undated (Box 6)
    - Briody, Stephen J.: Lisa, undated (Box 6)
    - Bryan, Bruce: The Ho-Ho Kam Horror (from: Weird Tales), undated (Box 6)
    - Capella, Garcia: Caravan to Kuthchemes, undated (Box 6)
    - de Caprona, Pierre: Correspondence and Necronomicon manuscript, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Chamberlain, Anne: Invitation to Tea. A Short Story, undated (Box 6)
    - Collier, John: Thus I Refute Beelzy (from: "Hauntings"), undated (Box 6)
    - Collins, Tess A.: The Feeling, undated (Box 6)
    - Comtois, Pierre: The Swan, undated (Box 6)
    - Cummin, Robert I.: Unfriendly Corporate Takeover - Old Style (from: Financial Analysts Journal, July/August 1982) (Box 6)
      reprint
    - Curtis, Carlow: The Dirty Dictionary: One Thousand Words, Terms, and Phrases You Won't Find in Your Dictionary (A Brief Sample), undated (Box 6)
      typescript with handwritten list of more words and clipping of "The Complete Gay Dictionary" from "Male Swinger"
    - Das, Manoj: Man Who Lifted the Mountain, 1979 (Box 12)
    - Derleth, August: Something From Out There (from "Weird Tales"), undated (Box 6)
      xerox copy of publication
    - Dimeo, Steven: Only Molds. A Short Story, undated (Box 6)
    - Dunsany, Lord (aka Edward Plunkett): miscellaneous writings by and on the author, miscellaneous documents re author, 1912-1972 and undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Folder 1: typescript with poems by Lord Dunsany (1919-1954), typescript of "Between Dunsany and Fingall" by John Boardman, typescript of "Beyond the Fields We Know: An Appreciation of Lord Dunsany and the Effect He Has Had on the Writing of Adult Fantasy" by Lois E. Newman, xerox copy of review on Lord Dunsany's "Correting Nature" by anonymous from "The Countryman. A Quarterly Non-Party Review and Miscellany of Rural Life and Work for the English-speaking World" (Vol. 42, No. 1, Autumn 1950), "The Plays by Lord Dunsany" by Clayton Hamilton from "The Bookman" (Vol. 44, no. 5, January 1917), xerox copy of "Introduction" (1912) by William Butler Yeats from an "Selections from the Writings of Lord Dunsany"; Folder 2: incl. correspondence of Lin Carter with various and miscellaneous notes and materials re author
    - Elder, Alona: My Cup of Tea, undated (Box 6)
    - Englehart, Richard: The Pleasuring of Millie, undated (Box 6)
    - Eshbach, Lloyd Arthur: Sister Abigail's Collection, undated (Box 6)
    - Everts, R. Alain: William Hope Hodgson: Night Pirate, 1987 (Box 12)
    - Ferguson, Malcolm M.: The Impressario and the Imp, undated (Box 6)
    - Gabriel's Gazette. An East Coast Newsletter of The Gabriel Project and Clear Light Center, Fall 1983 (Box 6)
      hard copy
    - Green, Roger Lancelyn: The City of the God, undated (Box 6)
    - Green, Roger Lancelyn: The Wood that Time Forgot: A Midsummer Night's Tale, 1949 (Box 12)
    - Halley, Meredith: The Stone Secret, 1983; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Folder 1: typescript with handwritten notes without main title ("The Stone Secret") incl. the chapters "1. Others," "2. The Stone," "3. The Presence," "4. The Sickness," "5. Orren," "6. The Flight," "7. The Testing," "8. The Road," "9. The North," "10. Orghuls!", "11. The White Huntress," "12. Secret Things," "13. The Hounds," "14. The Survivors," "15. Hunted," "16. Healer," "17. South," "18. The Woman-Thing," "19. The Stranger," "20. The Hole," "21. Lost," "22. The Welcome," "23. Rorn," "24. The Storm," "25. The Ending," (pp. 5-213, p. 142 missing); Folder 2: second typescript (possibly duplicate)
    - Hanisco, Bill: The Hitchhiker, 1985 (Box 6)
      typescript with accompanying letter to Carter dated 02/25/1985 re a possible publication in "Weird Tales"
    - Hawthorne, Nathaniel: The Minister's Black Veil. A Parable, undated (Box 6)
    - Heald, Hazel: Out of the Eon, undated (Box 6)
    - Herbert, John M.: Visit, undated (Box 6)
    - Hodgson, William Hope: Night Pirate. Volume One: An Annotated Bibliography Of Published Works 1902-1987, compiled and edited by Joseph Bell, undated (Box 6)
      bound typescript
    - Howard, Richard: Fortune 1 Cent, undated (Box 6)
    - Howard, Robert E.: The Garden of Fear, 1945 (Box 12)
    - Howard, Robert E.: miscellaneous material, 1972-1973 and undated; 4 folders (Box 6)
      incl. typescript in two parts with handwritten notes of "The Hyborian Age, arranged and edited by John D. Clark, PhD" (incl. "An Informal Biography of Conan the Cimmerian by Clark and P. Schuyler Miller"); xerox copy of publication of "The Thing on the Roof" (from "The Dark Man and Others") and illustrated typescript of "Desire and Other Erotic Poems" by Robert E. Howard, illustrated by Frank Frazetta; typescripts of "The Door in the World" and "The Gondarian Man" with accompanying letters to Carter dated 10/31/1972 and 01/09/1973 re Howard publications (originally in a folder labeled "Unpublished Tales"); typescript of "The Robert E. Howard Fantasy Biblio, compiled by Robert Weinberg, published by Mike Deckinger and Robert Weinberg
    - Howard, Robert: unpublished poems, undated (Box 10)
    - Huff, Kenneth: The Fortress of Shaitan, undated (Box 6)
      incomplete typescript (pp. 1-34)
    - The Intergalactic Reporter (Vol. 10, no. 9, September 1986; Vol. 12, no. 1, January 1988), 1986-1988 (Box 6)
      typescript copies (incomplete for 01/1988 with only first page)
    - Jackson, Shirley: The Lottery, 1948 (Box 6)
      xerox copy from publication
    - Jones, K. L.: They/Paranoia, undated (Box 6)
    - King, Stephen: The Plant, 1983 (Box 6)
      xerox copies of single chapters
    - Klein, Theodor Eibon Donald: A Dreamer's Tales, undated (Box 6)
    - Kuttner, Henry: The Citadel of Darkness/Cursed be the City, undated (Box 6)
      incomplete typescripts (pp. 95, 230-233)
    - LaBarbera, Damon: The Old Friend, undated (Box 6)
    - Lamb, J. J.: Stray, undated (Box 6)
    - LeGuin, Ursula K.: The Ones Who Walk Away From Omelas, undated (Box 6)
    - Livings, Earl: Recorded for Posterity/Retribution, 1984 (Box 6)
      typescript with accompanying letter by author to Carter dated 03/12/1094
    - Lovecraft, Howard Phillips: from "Crypt of Cthulhu," no. 43, 1983 Nov. 1 (Box 6)
      xerox copy of publication of "The Tree on the Hill" (co-authored by Duane W. Rimel) and "The Wanderer's Return"
    - Lovecraft, Howard Phillips (aka Ec'h-Pi-El): Selected Letters, 1930s (Box 6)
      xerox copies of publication of lettes by Lovecraft
    - Ludwig, David R.: The Neighbors, undated (Box 6)
    - Lumley, Brian: from "Crypt of Cthulhu," no. 14 and 19 and "Fantasy Tales", St. John's Eve 1983 (06/23/1983), Candlemas 1984 (02/02/1984), undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
      xerox copy of publications of "Swamp Call" (from issue no. 14, 1983), and "See Fret" and "Mammoth Rider" (from issue no. 19, 1984), xerox copy of publication of "City Out of Time" and "Mylakhrion the Immortal"
    - Magic Cities, ca. 1940, 1970 Nov. (Box 6)
      series of photographs with handwritten note by "RLG"
    - Master Monograph. Neophyte Section. Rosicrucian Order AMORC, no. 5, no year, undated (Box 6)
    - McIntosh, Pat: "The Trappings of Fantasy," in Andruil Sword and Sorcery, no. 5, 1975 (Box 10)
    - McLaughlin, Mark Anthony: The Room at the End of the Hall/Mondrago House, undated (Box 6)
    - Merritt, Abraham Grace (aka W. Fenimore): Poems, prose, and correspondence re publications, 1900s-1972 and undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Folder 1: xerox copy of publication of "Cosmos. Chapter Eleven. The Last Poet and the Robots" (originally loose pages); Folder 2: incl. letters by Walter J. Wentz to Carter dated 01/22/1972, 02/06/1972, undated re planned publication of Merritt poems; typescript of the short story "The Pool of the Stone God" by W. Fenimore (aka A. Merritt) from "American Weekly" (09/1923); typescripts and xerox copies of Merrits poems ("Fisher! Fisher!" from "Creep, Shadow!"; "Fragments From the Far Youth of A. Merritt": "Sylvane - The Silver Birches" and "Song for Wood Horns" from the fanzine "Nepenthe," no. 1, 1940; "In the Cathedral, Easter 1930" and "Court of the Moon (A Fragment)" and "Screens" from "Nepenthe," no. 2, 1942 (?); "The Birth of Art" from "Bohemia (1904); "The Ballad of the Cub" from "Philadelphia Inquirer" (?, 1902), "Old Trinity Churchyard (5 A. M., Spring)" from "Stirring Science Stories" (2/1942))
    - Moncrif, Augustin-Paradis de: Rival Souls: A Fable from "The Adventures of Zeloide and Amanzarifdine", undated (Box 6)
    - Munn, H. Warner: Fimmilene, The Spae-Wife, 1972 Nov. 20 (Box 6)
      typescript and accompanying letter by author to Carter dated 11/20/1972
    - Nashe, Thomas: Spring. The Sweet Spring, undated (Box 6)
    - Niekas. Science Fiction and Fantasy. "The Too-Long Fanzine," no. 30, 1982 (Box 6)
    - Nolane, Richard D.: The Thing in the Speed Queen (L'Habitant de Speed Queen), translated from the French by Joe F. Randolph, undated (Box 6)
    - The Old Professor: Random Jottings from Our Notebook, 1976 and undated (Box 6)
      typescripts with handwritten notes, incl. The Hinckey/Lovecraft Correspondence," "Science Discovers a Cure for the Pip," "Understanding the Universe," "Back to King's Fut's Tomb," "The Curse on King Put's Tomb"; hard copy of "Anduril. Magazine of Fantasy," no. 6, 1976 with two stories from "Random Jottings from Our Notebook" ("Tolkien and Me (or is it 'I')," "How I discovered Vulcan")
    - Pickett, Susan: Three in a Basket, undated (Box 7)
    - Pomeroy, Bradley: The Icy Tide, 1984 Mar. (Box 7)
      typescript with accompanying letter by author to Carter dated 03/26/1984
    - Porcelain, Sidney: novel fragment, 1971 Jun. (Box 7)
      typescript of chapter 12 of unidentified novel with accompanying memos by author to Carter dated 06/24/1971 and 06/26/1971
    - Price, Robert M.: Beneath the Tombstone, undated (Box 7)
    - Riley, Bradford: Thongor at the End of Time (screenplay), undated (Box 12)
    - Roche, S.: From Whence They Came, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Salonia, John and Tracey: Dark Eyes, undated (Box 7)
    - Schultz, David E.: Azaloth (from "Spoor," no. 1, 1974), 1973/1974 (Box 7)
    - Smith, Carol Jones: The Man Who Walks the Stars. Clark Ashton Smith, undated (Box 7)
    - Stockton, Frank R.: The Lady or the Tiger?, undated (Box 7)
    - Stoker, Bram: The Squaw, undated (Box 7)
    - Subotsky, Milton: Thongor in the Valley of Demons. Screenplay. From the Novel "The Wizard of Lemuria" by Lin Carter, 1979 Apr. (Box 7)
      typescript, "Revised: April, 1979"
    - Sutton, Paul: Lord and Master, 1984 Mar. (Box 7)
      typescript with accompanying letter by author dated 03/16/1984
    - Taylor, John Alfred: Cold Dead Fingers, undated (Box 7)
    - Tem, Steve Rasnic: Mother Hag, Cherokee, Moths, undated; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Tierney, Robert L.: The Fire of Mazda; The Nameless City/Harag-Kolath (from "Crypt of Cthulhu," no. 24), Lammas 1984 (08/01/1984) and undated; 2 folders (Box 7)
      incomplete typescript (pp. 41-59, end); xerox copy of publications in "Crypt of Cthulhu"
    - Tiley, Valerie: Epistle to Ambrose, undated (Box 7)
    - Tolkien, John Ronald Reuel: The Dragon's Visit, One Upon a Time, undated (Box 7)
      typescripts of poems
    - Unidentified: North Shore, undated (Box 7)
      typescript with handwritten notes incl. ch. "21. The Perpetual Honeymoon"
    - Van Arnam, David G. et al: "The Reader's Guide to Barsoom and Amtor,", 1963 (Box 10)
    - Weaver, George Russell: The Enrichment of Life, undated (Box 7)
      incomplete xerox copy of publication (pp. 207-209)
    - Weinberg, Robert: A Reader's Guide to the Cthulhu Mythos, 1969 (Box 12)
- Correspondence, 1945-1988 and undated; 2
  - Correspondence written by Carter, 1945, 1969, and undated (Box 7)
    correspondence to various recipients, incl. letter by Carter from VA Hospital about his health status
  - Correspondence addressed to Carter re overdue bills and other grievances, 1981-1988 (Box 7)
    past due reminder notices, legal letters, and lettes by authors re outstanding payments
  - Correspondence addressed to Carter by year, 1962-1988 and undated; 20 folders (Box 7)
    personal correspondence addressed to Carter as well as correspondence re publications, et al.
  - General correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 10)
  - Weird Tales editor correspondence, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Weird Tales rejection letters, 1987 (Box 10)
  - Eaton, Miles and Phil Barker incoming letters, 1949-1950 (Box 10)
  - Asimov, Isaac, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Berglund, Edward, 1974-1975 (Box 10)
  - de Camp, Sprague and Catherine, 1985-1987 (Box 10)
  - del Ray, Lester, 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - Meyer, Fred, 1980-1987 (Box 10)
  - Wollheim, Donald, 1985-1987 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence from authors, 1985-1987 (Box 10)
    Largely "get well" cards, notes
- Notes and Reference Materials, 1931-1987 and undated; 3
  Various papers and printed works created or collected by Carter outside of his drafts and correspondence. Includes some zines and catalogs as well as notes and untitled scraps that arrived loose and unaffiliated with other items.
  - Notebooks, 1982, 1986-1987, and undated; 5 folders (Box 7)
    containing mainly notes on writings and drafts as well as some personal notes, some containing note "began on" on first page
  - Notebooks, undated; 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Notes pages, manuscripts, undated; 2 folders (Box 8)
    single pages with various notes re daily and personal life as well as writing
  - Notes pages, typescripts, undated (Box 8)
    single pages with various notes and excerpts re writing as well as personal notes
  - Book concepts, undated (Box 8)
    folder label by Carter, various notes, excerpts, drafts, and materials re writing
  - Odds and Ends of Curious Information, undated (Box 8)
    folder label by Carter, various newspaper and magazine clippings and notes by Carter
  - Letterhead Art, undated (Box 8)
    folder label by Carter, clippings of pictures from various sources
  - Newspaper Clippings from "The New York Times", 1971, 1973, and undated (Box 8)
    various clippings re archeological, anthropological, fossile discoveries, etc.
  - Newspaper, Magazine, Book Clippings, and Business Cards from various sources, undated (Box 8)
    miscellaneous clippings of pictures, cartoons, ads, and articles (incl. "Science for Writers," "John Dee," etc.)
  - Art/Illustrations, undated (Box 8)
    folder label by Carter, various clipped images, playing cards, postcards, drawings, etc.
  - Decor, undated (Box 8)
    folder label by Carter, various magazine and newspaper clippings and notes with decor ideas, incl. floor plan of Carter's apartment and notes on "Decor Ideas"